Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
＜栄光の日 生まれの
ひびと
弟･日々人は➡
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
日本人初の
ムーンウォーカーとなった＞
＜月面望遠鏡建設を望む➡
Older brother Mutta seeks to become an astronaut, and keep his promise to former teacher Sharon,
恩師･シャロンとの
約束を果たすため➡
兄･六太は
宇宙飛行士を目指す＞
to build a telescope on the moon.
Mutta's made it through the first round, but he keeps running into trouble.
＜選抜試験を
かろ
辛うじて突破するが➡
訓練中もトラブルの連続！
筆記試験では最低点＞
On the written test, he scores the lowest.
＜暴走教官が
飛行訓練の担当になる始末＞
And as a result, he's assigned to a wild flight instructor.
＜だが 困難に揉まれたおかげで➡
However, the older brother Mutta
has yet to realize that he's rapidly learning the lessons he'll need to become an astronaut.
宇宙飛行士の大事な資質を➡
猛スピードで
身に付けていることに➡
兄･六太は
まだ気づいていない＞
なんば
(南波六太)＜月面で谷に落ちても
壊れないバギー＞
A buggy that won't take damage if it falls into a ravine...
＜あるいは 落ちないバギー＞
Or a buggy that won't fall.
道なき月面に 道を映し出す！
We can create roads on the roadless moon!
ナサ
あと ＮＡＳＡに
熱意さえあれば…｡
We only need NASA's passion
我々の この案は実現できます｡
for this plan to work!
(バトラー)では 結果は
追って連絡する｡
Then we'll get back to you in a few days.
《私が月に行けるかどうか…｡➡
My chances of going to the moon
全ては この結果に
かかっている！》
rest on the outcome of this presentation.
It's just obvious that the more you put in your bag
The heavier it gets
The harder I work, the closer I get to my goal
But I'm just not getting there fast enough
I gaze at the night sky but it doesn't calm me down
Now that you've heard how loud my heart's beating
Let's take a trip outside
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of dreams and reality
I'm currently updating the canvas of my dreams
With a glittering universe and a blue earth
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of facades and honesty
I'm currently conversing with the canvas of my dreams
On this orbit of fate
With a fire in my belly
#74 Magic Trick
I liked the windshield idea.
フロントウインドウの案
私は いいと思いましたよ｡
私も！
輸送費のことも ちゃんと
考慮している点が えらい｡
As did I.
I was impressed by the fact that they considered transportation costs.
バギーを新たに作って 月へ
送るには ４０億ドルは必要だが➡
Building a new buggy and sending it to the moon costs four billion dollars.
この案なら ４千万ドル程度で済む
送るのは ポリカーボネート製の➡
But their proposal would only cost ten million.
We'd only need to send one polycarbonate windshield,
ﾌﾛﾝﾄｳｲﾝﾄﾞｳ１枚と ｼﾞｮｲﾝﾄﾊﾟｰﾂと
ﾅﾋﾞｼｽﾃﾑのﾊﾞｯｸｱｯﾌﾟ用ﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞだけで➡
joint parts, and a backup drive for the navigation system...
いいわけですもんね｡
進めましょう これで｡
We should move forward with this plan.
賛成です｡
まさか 新人の宇宙飛行士が
こんな案を出してくるとは…｡
I concur.
I didn't foresee a rookie astronaut coming up with an idea like this.
室長 彼を技術班に研修させたのは
見事な采配ですな｡
Chief, assigning him to the engineers was a good call.
そうでしょう…ハハハ！
読みが冴えてましたよ｡
Indeed...
My instinct paid off.
Are you still worried about the doctors' diagnosis, Chief?
あずま
(吾妻)まだ 医師が言ってることが
心配ですか？室長｡
そりゃあ…そうでしょう｡
Yes... I suppose so.
ですが あの日々人ですよ｡
兄が 月の訓練をやりだすのを➡
However, we're talking about Hibito.
He isn't the type who'd be discouraged after hearing that his brother is training for lunar missions.
知ったとして 焦って不安に陥る
ような タイプではないでしょう｡
むしろ 兄を自分と
同じ目標に向かわせることで➡
In fact,
I believe that once his brother is aiming for the same goal,
奮い立つタイプであると
俺は見ています｡
he will be motivated to try harder.
君は ロナルド･クーパーを
知ってるか？
Do you know of Ronald Cooper?
聞いたことは｡
かつて ＮＡＳＡにいた｡
I've heard the name.
He used to work for NASA.
とても優秀な宇宙飛行士だ｡➡
He was a very good astronaut.
といっても 宇宙へは
行っていないんだけどね｡➡
But he never made it to space...
私より ６歳下の後輩だ｡私の
控えも よく務めてくれたよ｡➡
He was six years younger than I was.
He served as my backup multiple times.
もう ２０年以上前になるか…｡
It's been twenty years...
(ロナルド)⦅ハァ…ハァ…｡
アッ！⦆
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)Ｔ－３８の飛行訓練中に
事故で死にかけた➡
During T-38 training, Ronald nearly died in a crash.
ロナルドは その後 今のヒビトと
全く同じ症状になった｡➡
Afterward, he developed the same problem as Hibito,
パニック障害だ｡ロナルドは 空に
上がる事ができなくなったんだよ｡
a panic disorder.
Ronald could no longer fly...
(吾妻)治療は？
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)もちろん やってたさ｡➡
Was he treated?
Of course.
だが １年半以上やっても全く
効果はなく 先行くライバル達に➡
But after a year and a half without any sign of improvement,
Ronald realized he was falling behind his colleagues.
負い目を感じたロナルドは
宇宙飛行士を辞め➡
So he gave up on being an astronaut, and left NASA.
ＮＡＳＡを去った｡ヒビトが
ロナルドとは別人だという事は➡
I realize that Hibito and Ronald are different people.
分かっている 分かってはいるが…
慎重に やらせてくれ｡
But that said...
I want to be cautious.
So how did the presentation go?
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)で どうだったんだ？
プレゼンは｡
Well, our plan was accepted.
ああ…企画は通ったよ｡
バッチリね｡
Oh, then does that mean you'll start training for lunar missions?
お～！じゃあ ムッタも
いよいよ 月訓練の開始かい？
そりゃあ まだダメだったよ｡
企画が通っただけじゃ➡
Not yet, apparently...
Getting a plan approved isn't enough.
成果には ならんって事だろうね
やっぱ｡このままじゃ➡
It seems I'll be spending over half of the next year as an engineer.
来年も半分 技術者生活に
なりそうだな｡
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)お気の毒に｡
何か アンタと歩いてると➡
I'm sorry for you.
Is it just me, or does everyone stare when we walk around together,
まわりが見てくるんだよな
アレクサンダー｡
Alexander?
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)何でだろうね？
I wonder why that would be.
《ハァ…どうすりゃいいんだ？》
What do I do now?
I have to get Chief Butler to agree...
《結局は バトラー室長に認めて
もらうしか ねえんだろうな》
《上司に 自分の存在とか
実力を アピールする｡➡
I must promote myself to the boss.
何か そういうとこ
サラリーマン時代を思い出すな》
This reminds me of when I had an office job.
《だったら…》
In that case...
Maybe there is a way?
《何とかなるんじゃねえか？》
Jason Butler... NASA.
お～…出てきた｡
There we go.
｢アメリカ空軍士官学校卒業後
空軍パイロットとして活躍｡➡
"After graduating from the Air Force Academy, he served as an Air Force pilot.
空軍を一旦離れ ＭＩＴにて
宇宙航法学で博士号を取得｡➡
After leaving the Air Force, he completed an astronautics PhD at MIT."
元空軍パイロット…｣だったのか｡
He was a pilot in the Air Force?
《私は少し…焦っていた》
I was starting to worry.
《シャロンからの手紙だ》
It's a letter from Sharon.
Her handwriting had been gradually improving.
《少し書き慣れたかに見えた
文字も ある頃から➡
But lately, there were signs of her condition worsening.
病状の悪化を隠しきれず…》
《月に１～２通
届いていた手紙は➡
The letters that had arrived once or twice a month began coming less often.
次第にその数を減らしていった》
バーティカルクライムロール？
Huh? Vertical climb roll?
｢見る者には…ロケットの➡
"To spectators, it looks like a rocket launch..."
打ち上げのようにも
感じられるだろう｣｡
It's been a while since the last letter I received from Sharon.
《もう しばらく シャロンからの
手紙は届いていない》
《やっぱり…
元気ないのかな シャロン》
Could she be doing poorly?
《月へ行く訓練を始めたって
堂々と言えたら…➡
If I can tell her that I've started training for the moon...
言えたら それが…ちょっとぐらい
シャロンの希望にならね～かな》
Maybe that would be enough to give Sharon a little hope...
I found a thirty-year old interview.
ネットで３０年前の
インタビュー 見つけたんだ｡
自分を１人前のパイロットと
感じたのは いつですか？➡
The question was, "When did you first feel that you were a pilot?"
って問いに 宇宙飛行士になった➡
And astronaut Jason Butler's answer was...
ジェイソン･バトラーは
こう答えてる｡
バーティカルクライムロールを
教官の前で披露した時だ｡➡
When I first performed the vertical climb roll before my instructor.
ロールしながら急上昇していく
ド迫力の技だ｡➡
It's an impressive maneuver, in which you roll while ascending.
To spectators, it looks like a rocket launch.
見る者には ロケットの打ち上げの
ようにも感じられるだろう｡
空軍時代から私には
宇宙への強烈な憧れがあってね｡
I've been interested in space since I was still in the Air Force...
バーティカルは
その意志の現れでもあった｡
The vertical is how I express that interest.
あの時は このまま行けるなら
宇宙まで昇っていきたい➡
I was ready to fly all the way up, into space.
って気分だったよ｡
…で 私に そのバーティカル
クライムロールを教えてくれと？
You want me to teach you the vertical climb roll?
そう 頼むよアレックス｡
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)おや 省略してきたねぇ｡
Yep, can you do it, Alex?
Oh? You shortened my name...
Your name's too long...
なげ～もん 名前…｡
Alexander Nikolas Phillipos Medinakalos.
…って｡
ま 教えてやれないことはないが➡
Well, I don't mind teaching you the maneuver,
宇宙飛行士には
実に必要のない技だよ｡➡
but astronauts don't need to know it.
ましてや 空軍出身でもない
ムッタには｡
Especially since you didn't come from the Air Force.
I need to learn the maneuver to express my resolve.
必要なんだよ
｢意志の現れ｣として｡
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)室長に見せる気かい？➡
You're going to perform it for the chief?
君は実に…無謀な男だね｡
You're a crazy guy...
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)ＯＫ いいだろう！➡
Okay, I'll do it!
まずは見本を見せよう｡
５秒で行くよ｡➡
First, I'll show you how it's done...
Go is in five seconds.
ファイブ・フォー・スリー
５…４…３…｡
えっ もう!?
Five.
Four.
Wait, now?
Three.
Two.
ツー・ワン
２…１！
One.
パトリックは操縦の専門じゃない｡
Patrick isn't a dedicated operator.
Then what about Thomas?
じゃあ トーマスはどうですか？
ベテランですし｡
He's a veteran.
あいつはプライドが高すぎる｡
He doesn't know when to swallow his pride.
機長のアンガスと
ぶつかり合うのが目に見えてる｡
I can see him butting heads with the pilot, Angus.
じゃあ 誰にしましょうか…｡
Then, who can we use?
We could take Tara from the sub crew.
サブクルーからターラを上げよう｡
あれは男まさりの女だ｡➡
She's a strong woman.
このチームに合うだろう｡
(役員)なるほど…｡
She'd fit in perfectly.
I see...
そうなると
サブの空きには誰を入れます？
And who will replace her for the sub crew, then?
それは…新人の中から決める｡
We'll choose someone from the new astronauts.
誰にするかは…まだ わからん｡
At this point, I'm still not sure who.
ロナルド･クーパーは➡
Ronald Cooper left before he could make it to space.
一度も宇宙へ行くことなく
去ってしまった｡
おおお～！スゲエ！
Awesome!
見てたか ロナルド｡
俺のバーティカルクライムロール｡
Did you see my vertical climb roll, Ronald?
ええ！すごい迫力でしたよ
バトラーさん！
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)そうだろう｡
Yes, it was inspiring, Butler.
You bet...
オマエもやるといい｡
まずは教官に見せつけるんだ｡
You should give it a try.
First, you should show your instructor.
(ﾛﾅﾙﾄﾞ)いやぁ できますかね…｡
Uh, I'm not so sure about that...
オマエなら できるだろう｡➡
It ought to be easy enough for you.
あの ヘジテーションループを
たった３日でマスターした➡
You've been making a name for yourself, having mastered the hesitation roll in a mere three days as a new pilot.
驚異の新人って
ウワサになってるぜ｡
I'll teach you my secret.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)オレの秘密を教えてやる｡
誰にも言うなよ｡
Don't tell anyone else.
あんなアクロバット技…
宇宙飛行士がやる必要は➡
Most people say astronauts have no need to learn acrobatic maneuvers.
全くないって
よく言われるけどな➡
あれは実は魔法の裏技なんだ｡
(ﾛﾅﾙﾄﾞ)魔法の裏技？
But I consider it a kind of magic trick.
A magic trick?
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)己の出世欲｡➡
To climb up the ladder.
宇宙への憧れ｡➡
To express your love of space...
向上心！
To show your ambition!
そんなもんを
ストレートに伝える力が➡
The vertical climb roll has the power to accomplish all of those things.
バーティカルクライムロールには
秘められているんだ｡
オレはそうやって自分の士気を
室長達の脳裏に刻み込ませ➡
That's how I demonstrated my determination to the chief...
宇宙への切符を
勝ち取ることができた｡
And won my ticket to space.
…って そう思ってるね｡
At least, that's what I think.
へへ どこまで出世する気ですか｡
Heh, how high do you plan to climb?
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)そうだな｡宇宙飛行士を
存分にやり終えた後は…➡
Let's see...
After I've been an astronaut long enough,
宇宙飛行士室長の席にでも就いて
ふんぞり返りたいね｡ハハハッ！
I'll try for Chief of the NASA Astronaut Office, my feet propped on the desk.
オマエは どうしたい？
う～ん ボクは…｡
What about you?
Hmm... Me?
ボクはとにかく
早く宇宙へ行きたいですね｡
I just want to reach space as fast as I can.
ロナルド！大丈夫か オマエ!?
Ronald! Are you okay?!
あ…バトラーさん｡
Ah, Butler...
なんとか 全治３ヶ月程度のケガで
すみましたよ｡
I was lucky, so I'll make a full recovery in three months.
そうか…よかった｡
Oh, that's good...
バーティカルをやってて？
You weren't trying the vertical, were you?
いえ…霧が原因です｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)そ…そうか｡
No, I ran into some fog.
O-Oh...
危なかったです…｡
It was a close call.
もう死んだと思いました｡
I thought I was dead.
ま…まあ あれだ｡
魔法の裏技の話は忘れてくれ｡➡
W-Well, sure...
Forget what I said about that magic trick.
あんな技 無理に宇宙飛行士が
やる必要なんてないんだ｡
It isn't anything astronauts have to know.
(ﾛﾅﾙﾄﾞ)ハァ ハァ ハァ…➡
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ｡
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)おい！待てよ ロナルド｡
聞いたぞ｡
Hey! Wait, Ronald...
I heard the news.
オマエ 宇宙にも行かないまま
やめる気か？
You're quitting before you make it to space?
やめるなら
行ってからにしたらどうだ｡
Why not wait until you've gone?
肩書が宇宙飛行士になってから
６年半も過ぎたんですよ｡
Since I became an astronaut,
it's been eight and a half years.
この１年半は…なにをやっても
空にすら上がれませんでした｡
The last year and a half,
I haven't even managed to get airborne.
同期の仲間は どんどん宇宙へ
行ってるってのに…｡
Most of my contemporaries have gone to space.
Some make it in three years...
３年で行ける者もいりゃ
１０年以上かかる者もいる｡
Some have to wait ten.
そんなもん世の常だろ！
どこの世界でも同じだろう！
That's how the world works...
Regardless of your line of work.
ここにいて訓練を続けていれば
宇宙へ行けるなんて…➡
Even if I stay and keep training,
そんな保証は
ないじゃないですか！
there's no guarantee I'll ever get to space!
な ないな｡
No, there isn't...
But the people who made it there were those who stuck it out.
だが宇宙へ行った
人間ってのは➡
皆 そんなこと
承知で続けた者達だ｡
俺は続けるぞ｡
I'm going to stick it out.
And one day, I'll be sitting in the chief's office, my feet on the desk.
それで いつかは
室長のイスに座って➡
ふんぞり返る！➡
お前はどうしたいんだ？ロナルド｡
What do you want to do, Ronald?
現在
Hmm?
(バトラー)ミスターナンバ…｡
Mr. Nanba...
なぜ このアドレスを知ってる？
How did he get my e-mail address?
さてはアズマが…いや！
Must have been Azuma... Wait...
ありえる｡
It could have been him.
He wants to train for lunar missions?
月ミッションの希望か｡
Honestly... That man never gives up.
まったく あきらめの悪い男だ｡
いったい何のつもりだ｡
What's he thinking?
(役員)バトラーさん➡
Butler, care to join us for dinner?
夕食 一緒にいかがですか？
Ah, that sounds great... Sure.
あぁ～いいですね｡
行きますか｡
(役員)今日はどこで
食べましょうかね？
Where should we go tonight?
(バトラー)そうですね｡
Good question...
Oh, excuse me.
(バトラー)あのちょっと
すみません｡
どうしました？
いや…あの｡
What is it?
Uh, well...
１８時３０分ちょうどに➡
At around 6:30 PM, could you take us past Ellington Airport?
エーリントン飛行場の横を
通ってもらえますかね？
Just through the area is fine.
通るだけでいいので｡
何かあるんですか？
Is something supposed to happen?
(バトラー)いや～申し訳ない｡➡
Oh, sorry about this...
新人の宇宙飛行士が
見せたいものがあるとかで｡
One of the new astronauts has something to show me.
"Chief Butler, when you leave for dinner, could you drop by?"
｢バトラー室長 食事に出る際➡
寄ってもらうだけで
かまいません｣｡
まぁ どうせ
くだらんもんでしょうが➡
Well, I imagine it will be something silly, but I'd like to make sure.
一応 確認だけ｡
｢１８時半ちょうど➡
"Please look up,
エーリントン上空を
見てください｣｡
over Ellington Airport, around 6:30 PM."
《あぁ!?まさか…》
It can't be!
What do you want to do, Ronald?
⦅お前はどうしたいんだ？
ロナルド⦆
⦅僕はただ この１年半➡
For the last year and a half,
魔法の裏技だけでも➡
all I've wanted to do
出来るようになりたかった⦆
was to pull off that magic trick.
It's been so long since I looked up at the moon
Though it's always keeping a cold eye on me
Yeah, it always keeps a cold eye on me
I wanna rough up this rotten way home
But even if it makes me mad
I can't take my eyes off it. Yeah, I can't take my eyes off it
I can't take my eyes off that dazzling smile
What did I want back then?
What was I looking for?
I should've known my tears would take me to my dreams
Blow this gloomy reality away for me
I want to see how tiny our huge worries seem
From up in that dark ocean of space
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#75 My Hands
As Sharon continues treatment in Japan, she makes progress on her lunar observatory plan.
＜日本で療養中のシャロンは
月面望遠鏡計画に向けて➡
新たな行動に出る＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"My Hands"
"Dear Mutta...
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)＜ムッタへ｡
あなたが月に行ける頃➡
By the time you reach the moon,
私は あなたと話せなく
なっているかもしれません＞
I may not be able to speak to you."
Mr. Hibbit!
(ヒビット)誰かいる～？
イェーイ！
Anyone there?
Yay!
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰｲｰｸﾞﾙ)月へ行くには
あと２人 仲間がいる｡
You'll need two more members to reach the moon.
仲間を見つけることも
ミッションの１部なのだ｡
Recruiting is part of your mission.
(フレディドッグ)任せておけ｡
私は鼻がきく｡
Allow me to handle this. I have a sharp nose.
クン クン クン｡
Sniff, sniff, sniff.
Our comrades have a special, unique scent.
仲間になる者には
それなりの匂いがあるのだ｡
こっちか！
This way.
That fellow's fooling around.
なんて適当な奴だ｡
Ooh, there's a clinic!
(ヒビット)うぉ！病院だ｡
Sniff, sniff.
クンクン間違いない｡
仲間はここだ｡
Yes, a fellow comrade is definitely inside.
イェーイ！
Yay!
彼女こそが仲間だ｡
Sniff, sniff.
She is a comrade!
(カレンキャット)ウフフッ｡
あの人は仲間にしたくないよ｡
なんかこわい…｡
I don't want to recruit her.
She scares me...
確かに だが彼女の力は
いずれ必要になる｡
Indeed.
But we will need her help.
病院の無い月へ行くには
お医者さんが必要なのだ｡
There are no hospitals on the moon, so a doctor will be necessary.
イェーイ君の名は？
Yay! What's your name?
カレンキャットよ｡
Karen Cat.
Are you not feeling well?
あなたはどこが悪いのかしら？
うわぁ～！
Uh, I'm feeling fine...
僕は元気だよ｡
ニンジン食べる？
Want some carrots?
No, thank you.
いらニャいわ｡
私もらってもいい？
Can I have some?
You sure can.
おっ いいよ！君は？
Who are you?
私レッサーリンダ｡
I'm Red Panda Linda.
Carrots have lots of beta carotenes, and help prevent illness.
ニンジンって
ベータカロテンが豊富で➡
病気の抵抗力がつくし
美容にもいいの｡
They're also good for your skin.
えっ そうニャの？
Huh? Is that true?
《やっぱり もらおうかしら》
Perhaps I should have some.
You know a lot... That's awesome!
詳しいね君！スゴイや｡
Sniff, sniff.
クンクン間違いない｡
彼女も仲間だ｡
Yes, she is also a fellow comrade!
私の鼻がそう言っている｡
カレンキャットにレッサーリンダ｡
My nose never lies.
Karen Cat and Red Panda Linda...
僕らと一緒に
月へ行かないかい？
Wanna come to the moon with me?
月!?月かぁ～｡
悪くニャいわね｡
The moon? The moon, huh?
That doesn't sound too bad.
私は無理よ この脚じゃ｡
I can't go with my leg like this...
あニャたの脚は
もうほとんどニャおってるわよ｡
Your leg is more or less healed.
Eh?
えっ なに!?
Wh-What's going on?
(ヒビット)あっダミアンホーク｡
Whoa, it's Damian Hawk!
うそ!?立てた｡
私 立ってる｡
No way... I can stand.
I'm standing!
どうやら決まりだな｡
イエーイ！➡
That settles it.
Yay!
このメンバーで
月を目指そう！
This is the crew we'll take to the moon!
See you next week!